<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brownian Motion</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/</link><description>A collection of pseudorandom writings</description><atom:link href="https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2024 &lt;a href="mailto:jierueic@gmail.com"&gt;Jieruei Chang&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 02:49:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Monster of Lake Tahoe</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/the-monster-of-lake-tahoe/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written while procrastinating on linalg homework&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fish. Brine. The sound of waves rippling across midnight air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were rippling quite hard, in fact―the boat felt like it was about to capsize. But not too far away were the lights of the ports. Not too far away was home. Not too far away was my boy, who still thought his dad wrangled sea monsters for a living. I mean, he technically wasn’t wrong―the bluefin tuna I caught last week was quite a struggle. But it was nothing compared to the legendary Monster of Lake Tahoe, supposedly a hundred-ton tentacled beast that lurks beneath the waves. (Or something like that. The tale grows grander every time I hear it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boat rocked. It heaved with each crest and trough, its metal hull creaking like a chainsmoker trying to do deep meditative breathing. Water rushed across the deck; the radio crackled; the engine sputtered but powered onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some boats sink gracefully. Not mine. It fought. The metal bent and screamed as it was torn asunder. Water spilled into the ship’s guts, probably to the short-lived excitement of salmon in the cargo hold. The boat’s lights flickered off for the last time as the generator’s rumble gave way to momentary silence; the stern plunged into the water, taking me down with it; saltwater flooded into my nostrils and stung my eyes―I felt like I was swimming through molasses. Every movement was in slow motion. In the distance, silhouetted against the night sky, something (a wave?) rose from the water. I felt myself in the air, carried by some unseen force, something cold wrapping itself around me (the wind?)... And then I watched as lightning arced across the sky, briefly illuminating the mangled corpse of my boat (and something else?)...
And then I glimpsed the coast coming closer...
And then...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up coughing somewhere on the shoreline. Slowly my vision cleared, revealing a cloudless horizon ahead. I looked around. Out of the corner of my eye I caught a hint of a shape darting back beneath the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing but the sound of waves rippling across midnight air.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/the-monster-of-lake-tahoe/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 02:48:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bryant Park</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/bryant-park/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In Bryant Park&lt;br&gt;
there is a man&lt;br&gt;
with a chessboard.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Game?&lt;/em&gt; he asks,&lt;br&gt;
gesturing to the empty&lt;br&gt;
seat beside him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel another hand&lt;br&gt;
pulling against my own:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Come on. We’ll be late.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My eyes linger&lt;br&gt;
for a moment&lt;br&gt;
before glancing away.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/bryant-park/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:20:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/12_(number)</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/httpsenwikipediaorgwiki12_number/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;the number of years&lt;br&gt;
    in an orbital period of Jupiter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;three times four:&lt;br&gt;
the sixth composite&lt;br&gt;
the second semiperfect&lt;br&gt;
the largest number with a single-syllable name when written in the English Language&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a lunar year’s cycle&lt;br&gt;
a rhythm of stars&lt;br&gt;
    tracing pictures in the night sky&lt;br&gt;
a procession of animals across the heavens ―&lt;br&gt;
    fire, anew,&lt;br&gt;
    burning white-hot&lt;br&gt;
        like sparks of magnesium aflame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the number of books in the &lt;em&gt;Aeneid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
the number of pitches in a chromatic&lt;br&gt;
the number of years&lt;br&gt;
    we’ve been&lt;br&gt;
together&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/httpsenwikipediaorgwiki12_number/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 22:16:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Minutes in Three Styles: A Sketch</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/three-minutes-in-three-styles-a-sketch/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standard fare: 2½ cups white rice (plus a sprinkle of quinoa), 3½ cups water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/three-minutes-in-three-styles-a-sketch/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/three-minutes-in-three-styles-a-sketch/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 04:05:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Multiverse of Narratives</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/a-multiverse-of-narratives/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written for the PHS Student Newspaper (again)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest: I’m not much of a superhero fan. The recipes for most superhero movies today all seem pretty similar: take some guy with magical powers (and the ego to boot), throw him into some conundrum with the Villain of the Day, and have him fight his way through. Mix in some witty jokes, manufacture some sort of emotional moment to give an impression of sophistication, and wrap the whole thing with a special-effects budget that could rival the GDP of a small nation. And then, apparently, watch the box-office money rain down from the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/a-multiverse-of-narratives/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/a-multiverse-of-narratives/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 22:08:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pillars of Salt and Pillars of Sand</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/pillars-of-salt-and-pillars-of-sand/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Based on "A Little Cloud" by James Joyce; written with Aman Kapur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew couldn’t sleep. He glanced wearily at the bluish light emanating from his roommate’s desk ― in the glow, he could just about make out the hands of his watch, its hands forming a despairingly early hour. Outside the window lay darkness and silence; within, the rhythmic machine-gun fire of a mechanical keyboard, rattling the cramped tenth-floor dormitory room, scaring the sheep from Andrew’s mind as he tried in vain to count them. Sam was up to something again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/pillars-of-salt-and-pillars-of-sand/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/pillars-of-salt-and-pillars-of-sand/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 21:59:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>May the Best Duelist Win</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/may-the-best-duelist-win/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Highlands. Dreary, windswept, moody. Yellowing grass smeared into cliff faces of imposing rock; petrichor mixing with fumes of moss diffusing across the earth (Scotland, probably, by the looks of it). A figure emerges through the fog―pensive, contemplative, a hood of cashmere effortlessly concealing a dark gash down the side of his temple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/may-the-best-duelist-win/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/may-the-best-duelist-win/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 05:34:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Happily ever after...?</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/happily-ever-after/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written for The Princeton High School Tower Newspaper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why the hell should I care about fairy tales?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, my dear hypothetical friend, you should care because they’re fun. When was the last time you fought a dragon while riding a flying carpet? The last time you were a mermaid seeking to find a world above the waves? The last time you crawled through a wardrobe door and talked to a goat? But they're also a reflection of our social values — what morals does a society think are so important that they’re woven into some of the very first stories we tell our children?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/happily-ever-after/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/happily-ever-after/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 06:26:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Diving Into Myth</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/diving-into-myth/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adapted from an article I wrote for The Tower, the PHS student newspaper.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ocean is quite a poetic oxymoron. For hundreds of thousands of years, it has separated cultures with vast seas and treacherous storms, and yet it has also unified them in contemplating the same majestic waters. As they gazed, they thought of stories. What does the ocean hold, hidden beneath its seemingly endless waves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/diving-into-myth/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/diving-into-myth/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 02:08:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan, I hear you singing</title><link>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/taiwan-i-hear-you-singing/</link><dc:creator>Jieruei Chang</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Taiwan, I hear you singing —&lt;br&gt;
your wind from mountain&lt;br&gt;
to sea, your skyscrapers&lt;br&gt;
and rolling fields of rice, your air&lt;br&gt;
of incense and motorcycle fumes,&lt;br&gt;
your 7-Elevens and blistering sun&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taiwan, I hear you singing —&lt;br&gt;
there’ve been too many&lt;br&gt;
summers we’ve spent apart&lt;br&gt;
but though we’ve changed&lt;br&gt;
so much since we last met&lt;br&gt;
still&lt;br&gt;
you feel&lt;br&gt;
like home&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://knosmos.github.io/brownian/posts/taiwan-i-hear-you-singing/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 22:14:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>